A Guide to the Records of the Virginia Secretary of Public Safety, 1990; 1992; 1996; 1998-2010 (bulk 2002-2009)
Library of Virginia
- Series II. Correspondence and Supporting Documentation - Office of the Secretary, 1990; 1992; 1998-2009., Extent: 19.4 cubic feet (22 boxes). (Box 12-30)
  - Series II. Correspondence and Supporting Documentation - Office of the Secretary, Subseries D. Records of Assistant Secretary Dawn Smith, 2002-2008., Extent: 3.0 cu. ft. (boxes 26-28)
    - Virginia Citizen-Soldier Support Council
      - Virginia Citizen-Soldier Support Council Meeting, 5 April 2007. (Box 28, Folder 4)
      - Virginia Military Advisory Council and Virginia Citizen-Soldier Support Council Joint Meeting, 22 August 2007. (Box 28, Folder 5)
      - Virginia Citizen-Soldier Support Council Meeting, 3 December 2007. (Box 28, Folder 6)
      - Virginia Citizen-Soldier Support Council Meeting, 24 April 2008. (Box 28, Folder 6)
      - Virginia Citizen-Soldier Support Council Membership Lists, undated. (Box 28, Folder 6)
      - Meeting with Bob Crouch, Deputy Director of Public Safety and Eileen Filler-Corn, Deputy Director of the Virginia Liaison Office, 13 April 2004. (Box 28, Folder 7)
      - Virginia Military Advisory Council, 12 December 2003. (Box 28, Folder 8)
      - Virginia Military Advisory Council Meeting, 19 May 2004. (Box 28, Folder 8)
      - Virginia Military Advisory Council Meeting, 23 October 2006. (Box 28, Folder 8)
      - Correspondence, Press Releases, and Reports, 2002-2007. (Box 28, Folder 9)
      - 2005 Citizen-Soldier Legislation, 2005. (Box 28, Folder 10)
      - Family Relief Fund, SB 139/HB 628, 2006. (Box 28, Folder 10)
      - National Governors Association Reports, 2004-2006. (Box 28, Folder 11)
      - Miscellaneous Reports, 2006 and undated. (Box 28, Folder 12)
      - Miscellaneous Reports, 2004 and undated. (Box 28, Folder 13)
      - Photograph of Virginia Citizen-Soldier Support Council with Governor Mark Warner, undated. (Box 28, Folder 14)
    - Virginia Juvenile Enterprise Committee, 2006. (Box 28, Folder 15)
  - Series II. Correspondence and Supporting Documentation - Office of the Secretary, Subseries E. Records of Assistant Secretary/Deputy Secretary Marilyn Harris, 2002-2007., Extent: 1.35 cu. ft. (boxes 29-30)
    This subseries is housed in two boxes and is arranged alphabetically by agency or subject. It contains correspondence and subject files kept by Assistant/Deputy Secretary of Public Safety Marilyn Harris during the administration of Governor Mark R. Warner (2002-2006) and Governor Timothy M. Kaine (2006-2010). This series contains correspondence, email printouts, reports and studies, and memorandums. The bulk of the subseries focuses on gangs with a focus on allocation in 2004-2005 of a three-million-dollar federal grant to localities to combat gang activity throughout Virginia and the Public Safety Agency Gang Working Group/Interagency Anti-Gang Work Group.
    - FFY 2007 Congressional Briefing Material, Secretary of Public Safety John W. Marshall, ca. July 2006. (Box 29, Folder 1)
    - Governor's Office for Substance Abuse Prevention (GOSAP), Progress Report and Interagency Memorandum of Agreement, July 2005. (Box 29, Folder 2)
    - Governor's Office for Substance Abuse Prevention (GOSAP), Youth School Surveys, 2006. (Box 29, Folder 3)
    - Governor's Office for Substance Abuse Prevention (GOSAP), Youth School Surveys, 2007. (Box 29, Folder 4)
    - Strategic Highway Safety Plan, October 2006. (Box 29, Folder 5)
    - Gangs
      - Gang Violence Task Force Meeting, 19 November 2002. (Box 29, Folder 6)
      - 2003 (Box 29, Folder 7)
      - 2004 January to April (Box 29, Folder 8)
      - 2004 May to September (Box 29, Folder 9)
      - Court Service Unit Gang Awareness and Intervention Training, 30 September 2004 (part 1). (Box 29, Folder 10)
      - Court Service Unit Gang Awareness and Intervention Training, 30 September 2004 (part 2). (Box 29, Folder 11)
      - 2004 October to November (Box 29, Folder 12)
      - Gang Activity Initiatives Funding Meeting, 8 November 2004. (Box 29, Folder 13)
      - Gang Activity Initiatives Funding, Proposals for Review, 8 November 2004 (copy 1). (Box 29, Folder 14)
      - Gang Activity Initiatives Funding, Proposals for Review, 8 November 2004 (copy 2). (Box 29, Folder 15)
      - Gang Activity Initiatives Funding, Proposals for Review, 8 November 2004 (copy 3). (Box 29, Folder 16)
      - 2004 December to 2005 January (Box 29, Folder 17)
      - 2005 (Box 29, Folder 18)
      - Prevention Comes First-KIDsafe 4 Conference and Joint Leadership Summit, 11 December 2006. (Box 30, Folder 1)
      - Reference Material (Box 30, Folder 2)
      - Reference Material (Box 30, Folder 3)
- Series III. Decision Memoranda and Briefs, 2005-2010., Extent: 1.0 cubic feet (1 box). (Box 31)
  The Decision Memoranda and Briefs series is housed in one box and is arranged chronologically. This series documents the history of decision briefs sent by Public Safety agencies to the Secretary of Public Safety for approval. This series includes decision memoranda, decision briefs and supporting documentation from assigned state agency heads asking the Secretary's permission to perform a major function or policy initiative within their agency. Decision Briefs approved by the governor are located in the records of the Governor Tim Kaine's Policy Office, Series I. Decision Briefs (accession 44690).
  - 2005 (Box 31, Folder 1)
  - 2006 January-April (Box 31, Folder 2)
  - 2006 May (Box 31, Folder 3)
  - 2006 June (Box 31, Folder 4)
  - 2006 July-August (Box 31, Folder 5)
  - 2006 September-November (Box 31, Folder 6)
  - 2007 February-April (Box 31, Folder 7)
  - 2007 May (Box 31, Folder 8)
  - 2007 July (Box 31, Folder 9)
  - 2007 August (Box 31, Folder 10)
  - 2007 August (Box 31, Folder 11)
  - 2007 September-December (Box 31, Folder 12)
  - 2008 February (Box 31, Folder 13)
  - 2008 April (Box 31, Folder 14)
  - 2008 May (Box 31, Folder 15)
  - 2008 June (Box 31, Folder 16)
  - 2008 July (Box 31, Folder 17)
  - 2008 August-December (Box 31, Folder 18)
  - 2009 January (Box 31, Folder 19)
  - 2009 February (Box 31, Folder 20)
  - 2009 March (Box 31, Folder 21)
  - 2009 April (Box 31, Folder 22)
  - 2009 May (Box 31, Folder 23)
  - 2009 June (Box 31, Folder 24)
  - 2009 June (Box 31, Folder 25)
  - 2009 July (Box 31, Folder 26)
  - 2009 August (Box 31, Folder 27)
  - 2009 September (Box 31, Folder 28)
  - 2009 October (Box 31, Folder 29)
  - 2009 November-December (Box 31, Folder 30)
  - 2010 January (Box 31, Folder 31)
- Series IV. Federal Grant Funding, 2002-2009., Extent: 1.0 cubic feet (1 box). (Box 32)
  The Federal Grant Funding series is housed in one box and is arranged alphabetically by state agency. This series consists of the correspondence and supporting documentation sent and received by the office to and from agencies of the Public Safety Secretariat, including Criminal Justice Services, Emergency Management, Governor's Office for Substance Abuse Prevention (GOSAP), Juvenile Justice, and State Police regarding their request and receipts of federal grants
  - Criminal Justice Services, Dept. of, 2009. (Box 32, Folder 1)
  - Criminal Justice Services, Dept. of, 2009. (Box 32, Folder 2)
  - Criminal Justice Services, Dept. of, 2008. (Box 32, Folder 3)
  - Criminal Justice Services, Dept. of, 2008. (Box 32, Folder 4)
  - Criminal Justice Services, Dept. of, 2007. (Box 32, Folder 5)
  - Criminal Justice Services, Dept. of, 2006. (Box 32, Folder 6)
  - Criminal Justice Services, Dept. of, 2006. (Box 32, Folder 7)
  - Criminal Justice Services, Dept. of, 2006. (Box 32, Folder 8)
  - Criminal Justice Services, Dept. of, 2006. (Box 32, Folder 9)
  - Emergency Management, Dept. of, 2007. (Box 32, Folder 10)
  - Governor's Office for Substance Abuse Prevention (GOSAP), 2009. (Box 32, Folder 11)
  - Juvenile Justice, Dept. of, 2006. (Box 32, Folder 12)
  - Virginia State Police, 2002-2003. (Box 32, Folder 13)
  - Virginia State Police, 2004-2009. (Box 32, Folder 14)
- Series V. Legislative Files, 2002-2003; 2005-2009., Extent: 1.0 cubic feet (1 box). (Box 33)
  The Legislative Files series is housed in one box and is arranged chronologically. This series consists of legislation and supporting documentation affecting the Office of the Secretary of Public Safety, as well as state agencies assigned to the Secretariate. This series needs to be reviewed for confidential information before being served to public.
  - 2003 Legislative Session, 2002-2003. (Box 33, Folder 1)
  - 2006 Legislative Session, 2005. (Box 33, Folder 2)
  - 2007 Legislative Session, 2006. (Box 33, Folder 3)
  - 2007 Legislative Session, 2006. (Box 33, Folder 4)
  - 2007 Legislative Session, 2006. (Box 33, Folder 5)
  - 2008 Legislative Session, 2007. (Box 33, Folder 6)
  - 2008 Legislative Session, 2007. (Box 33, Folder 7)
  - 2008 Legislative Session, 2007. (Box 33, Folder 8)
  - 2008 Legislative Session, 2007. (Box 33, Folder 9)
  - 2009 Legislative Session, 2008. (Box 33, Folder 10)
  - 2009 Legislative Session, 2008. (Box 33, Folder 11)
  - 2009 Legislative Session, 2008. (Box 33, Folder 12)
  - 2010 Legislative Session, 2009. (Box 33, Folder 13)
  - 2010 Legislative Session, 2009. (Box 33, Folder 14)
  - 2010 Legislative Session, 2009. (Box 33, Folder 15)
  - 2010 Legislative Session, 2009. (Box 33, Folder 16)
- Series VI. Special Projects and Studies, 2002; 2004-2009., Extent: 1.35 cubic feet (2 boxes). (Box 34-35)
  The Special Projects and Studies series is housed in two boxes and is arranged alphabetically by state agency. This series documents the Secretary of Public Safety's interaction with and oversight of various projects and studies. This series may include, but is not limited to, projects and studies associated with Governor's initiatives, issues, and topics.
  - Alcoholic Beverage Control, Dept. of, 2007. (Box 34, Folder 1)
  - Correctional Education, Dept. of, 2006-2009. (Box 34, Folder 2)
  - Corrections, Dept. of, 2008-2009. (Box 34, Folder 3)
  - Corrections, Dept. of, 2005. (Box 34, Folder 4)
  - Corrections, Dept. of, 2006. (Box 34, Folder 5)
  - Corrections, Dept. of, 2006. (Box 34, Folder 6)
  - Corrections, Dept. of, 2006. (Box 34, Folder 7)
  - Corrections, Dept. of, 2006. (Box 34, Folder 8)
  - Corrections, Dept. of, 2006. (Box 34, Folder 9)
  - Corrections, Dept. of, 2006-2007. (Box 34, Folder 10)
  - Corrections, Dept. of, 2007. (Box 34, Folder 11)
  - Criminal Justice Services, Dept. of, 2005-2006. (Box 34, Folder 12)
  - Criminal Justice Services, Dept. of, 2007-2008. (Box 34, Folder 13)
  - Criminal Justice Services, Dept. of, Biased-Based Policing Study (1 of 2), 2004. (Box 34, Folder 14)
  - Criminal Justice Services, Dept. of, Biased-Based Policing Study (2 of 2), 2004. (Box 34, Folder 15)
  - Emergency Management, Dept. of, 2005-2009. (Box 34, Folder 16)
  - Fire Programs, Dept. of, 2006. (Box 34, Folder 17)
  - Forensic Science, Dept. of, 2006-2009. (Box 34, Folder 18)
  - Juvenile Justice, Dept. of, 2006. (Box 34, Folder 19)
  - Military Affairs, Dept. of, 2007. (Box 34, Folder 20)
  - Public Safety Studies, 2002. (Box 34, Folder 21)
  - Public Safety Studies, 2005. (Box 34, Folder 22)
  - Public Safety Studies, 2006. (Box 34, Folder 23)
  - Public Safety Studies, 2007. (Box 34, Folder 24)
  - Public Safety Studies, 2007. (Box 34, Folder 25)
  - Public Safety Studies, 2007. (Box 34, Folder 26)
  - Public Safety Studies, 2009. (Box 34, Folder 27)
  - Virginia State Police, 2005-2006. (Box 34, Folder 28)
  - Virginia State Police, 2006. (Box 34, Folder 29)
  - Virginia State Police, 2007-2009. (Box 34, Folder 30)
  - Governor's Office for Substance Abuse Prevention (GOSAP), 2006-2009. (Box 35, Folder 1)
  - Traffic Safety Initiative, 2006. (Box 35, Folder 2)
  - Traffic Safety Initiative, 2006. (Box 35, Folder 3)
  - Traffic Safety Initiative, 2006. (Box 35, Folder 4)
  - Traffic Safety Initiative, 2006. (Box 35, Folder 5)
  - Traffic Safety Initiative, 2006. (Box 35, Folder 6)
  - Veterans Services, Dept. of, 2006-2007. (Box 35, Folder 7)
  - Virginia Commission on Youth, 2006. (Box 35, Folder 8)